{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What does the Morse code abbreviation 'AA' represent?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Answer",
        "b": "All after",
        "c": "Antenna",
        "d": "End of message"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "'AA' in Morse code does not represent 'Answer.'",
        "b": "'AA' stands for 'All after' in Morse code, indicating that the message following this abbreviation is intended for a specific station.",
        "c": "'AA' is not related to 'Antenna.'",
        "d": "'AA' does not signify the 'End of message.'"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Morse code, 'B4' stands for?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Broadcast",
        "b": "Before",
        "c": "Bad",
        "d": "Back or break"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "'B4' in Morse code does not stand for 'Broadcast.'",
        "b": "'B4' in Morse code is an abbreviation for 'Before,' signifying a reference to something that occurred earlier",
        "c": "'B4' in Morse code does not stand for 'Bad.'",
        "d": "'B4' in Morse code does not stand for Back or break."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does 'HW?' signify in Morse code communication?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "How do you copy me? What about you?",
        "b": "Happy weekend",
        "c": "Hear well",
        "d": "High wattage"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "'HW?' is a Morse code abbreviation used to inquire about the quality of reception between stations.",
        "b": "HW? does not signify 'Happy weekend' in Morse code communication.",
        "c": "HW? does not stand for 'Hear well' in Morse code. It is a query about reception quality.",
        "d": "HW? does not represent 'High wattage' in Morse code."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "When using Morse code, '73' is commonly understood as?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "A friendly greeting",
        "b": " Best regards",
        "c": "Bad luck",
        "d": "Backward motion"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "'A friendly greeting' is not the primary meaning of '73' in Morse code; it is typically used to convey 'Best regards.' This option is incorrect.",
        "b": "73' is a widely recognized Morse code abbreviation used to convey 'Best regards'.",
        "c": "'Bad luck' is not a commonly understood meaning of '73' in Morse code. This option is incorrect.",
        "d": "'Backward motion' is not a commonly understood meaning of '73' in Morse code. This option is incorrect."
        
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the Morse code abbreviation 'DR' indicate?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Drive carefully",
        "b": "Down",
        "c": "Dear",
        "d": "Double response"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "'Drive carefully' is not a common Morse code abbreviation.",
        "b": "'Down' is not a Morse code abbreviation for 'DR.'",
        "c": "'DR' is an abbreviation in Morse code that typically represents 'Dear,' often used in personal messages.",
        "d": "'Double response' is not a common Morse code interpretation for 'DR.'"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Morse code Abbreviations, 'BTW' is used to convey?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Back to work",
        "b": "By the way",
        "c": "Between",
        "d": "Best wishes"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Back to work is not a Morse code abbreviation.",
        "b": "By the way",
        "c": "Between' is abbreviated as 'BTWN' in Morse code, not 'BTW'",
        "d": "Best wishes is abbreviated as 73 in Morse code, not BTW"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Morse code abbreviation representation corresponds to the letter 'U'?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "'...-' and hi",
        "b": "--. and your",
        "c": "...-. and unit",
        "d": "..- and you."
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "This option does not represent the Morse Code abbreviation",
        "b": "This option does not represent the Morse Code abbreviation",
        "c": "This option does not represent the Morse Code abbreviation",
        "d": "..- in Morse code represents the letter 'U,' and 'you' is a common English word. "
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Morse code abbreviation 'CBA'?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Callbook address",
        "b": "Corrected broadcast announcement",
        "c": "Circuit breaker alert",
        "d": "Continuous broadcasting arrangement"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "CBA is a Morse code abbreviation used to represent 'Callbook address,' often used in amateur radio communication.",
        "b": "Corrected broadcast announcement is not a Morse code abbreviation.",
        "c": "Circuit breaker alert is not a Morse code abbreviation",
        "d": "Continuous broadcasting arrangement is not a Morse code abbreviation"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does 'SK' signify in Morse code communication?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Special knowledge",
        "b": "Start keying",
        "c": "Stop keying",
        "d": "Silent key"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Special knowledge is not a Morse code abbreviation therefore option is incorrect",
        "b": "Start keying is not a Morse code abbreviation",
        "c": "In Morse code, 'SK' is used to indicate 'Stop keying.' It is often transmitted at the end of a conversation or transmission to inform the receiving station that the sender has finished transmitting.",
        "d": "Silent key is not a Morse code abbreviation"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Morse code, 'OPR' is commonly used to represent?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Operation",
        "b": "Operator",
        "c": "Open relay",
        "d": "Overpowered"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "This option is not represent Morse Code OPR Abbreviation",
        "b": "OPR in Morse code stands for 'Operator' and is often used in various contexts to refer to operational activities.",
        "c": "Open relay is not a Morse code abbreviation ",
        "d": "Overpowered is not a Morse code abbreviation"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "When a Morse code operator uses 'CONDX,' they are referring to?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Complex directions",
        "b": "Conduction and transmission",
        "c": "Conditions",
        "d": "Continuous Diving"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Complex directions is not a Morse code abbreviation",
        "b": "Conduction and transmission is not a Morse code abbreviation",
        "c": "'CONDX' in Morse code is an abbreviation for Conditions.",
        "d": "Continuous Diving is not a Morse code abbreviation"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does 'RX' signify in Morse code?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Re-examine",
        "b": "Receiver",
        "c": "Retransmit",
        "d": "Receiver operating"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Re-examine is not a Morse code abbreviation",
        "b": "'RX' in Morse code stands for 'Receiver,' referring to the equipment used to receive signals.",
        "c": "Retransmit is not a Morse code abbreviation",
        "d": "Receiver operating is not a Morse code abbreviation ,it is the Receiver"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does 'PSE' signify in Morse code communication?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Please",
        "b": "Patient",
        "c": "Potential",
        "d": "Postpone"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "PSE is a Morse code abbreviation for 'Please,' used to make polite requests or inquiries.",
        "b": "This option does not represent PSE in Morse Code abbreviations",
        "c": "Potential is not a Morse Code abbreviation" ,
        "d": "Postpone is not a Morse Code abbreviation"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Morse code, what does the abbreviation 'FER' stand for?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "For",
        "b": "Fine business",
        "c": "Forward",
        "d": "Frequency"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "'FER' in Morse code represents 'For'.",
        "b": "Fine business is abbreviated as FB in Morse code, not FER",
        "c": "This is not the option for FER",
        "d": "Frequency does not represent for Morse Code abbreviation FER"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the Morse code abbreviation 'CQ'?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "To request silence on the channel",
        "b": "To indicate the end of the message",
        "c": "General call for a QSO",
        "d": "To apologize for interference"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "To request silence on the channel is not a Morse code abbreviation for the given abbreviation ",
        "b": "To indicate the end of the message is abbreviated as AR in Morse code, not CQ‚Äù",
        "c": "CQ is a Morse code abbreviation used as a general call to invite any station to establish communication (QSO).",
        "d": "To apologize for interference does not represent for Morse Code abbreviation CQ"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    }
  ]
}
